♪ ♪
Subtitles by explosiveskull
( TICKING )
( MUFFLED , INDISTINCT CHATTER )
( FAN BUZZING AND WHOOSHING )
DOCTOR : You 're not cold or anything , are you ?
Everything all right ?
Are you taking any medication ?
- Hmm ? - ( MAN LAUGHING )
Thank you .
How are you doing this morning ?
Did you have a restful sleep last night ?
- MAN : Oh , yeah . - ( DOOR CREAKS SHUT )
- DOCTOR : You did ? - MAN : I did .
- Any dreams ? - Nope .
DOCTOR : Sometimes we don 't remember our dreams , you know ?
- MAN : That 's right . - ( DOOR CLANKS SHUT )
DOCTOR : We do dream , but we don 't remember
- when we wake up . - No .
DOCTOR : But if we are dreaming some
just before we wake up , we remember those .
MAN : That 's right .
DOCTOR : Did you know ...
A little , uh ... uh , useful information .
( INDISTINCT ANNOUNCEMENT OVER P.A. )
- MAN : Yeah . - DOCTOR : When we wake up
and say , " The whole night ,
I was dreaming this and that and everything , "
- it 's only 45 minutes maximum . - ( ORCHESTRAL MUSIC PLAYS )
- Did you know that ? - Yeah . No , I did not . Yeah .
DOCTOR : So the ordinary dream is ten or 15 minutes .
I 'll see you all later .
- Where are you going ? - I 'm going to see my patients .
DANA : Testing . Testing .
Check , check , check . One , two , three .
Testing . One , two , three .
We are now at Smith 's Grove ,
uh , rehabilitation facility .
AARON : We 're here today to interview a patient
that 's spent the last 40 years in captivity
and , by all accounts , has not uttered a word .
This monster ...
- ( BUZZING ) - ( LOCK CLUNKS )
- Good afternoon . - Good afternoon .
I 'm Dr. Ranbir Sartain .
- Great to finally meet you . - ( DOOR CLOSES )
Thank you so much for taking the time to meet with us today .
We were hoping to have this opportunity
before he 's transferred to the new facility .
Glass Hill is far less accommodating .
Glass Hill is the pit of hell .
For years , he 's been kept here to be studied .
I suppose the state has lost interest
in discovering anything further .
Well , that 's why we 're here .
SARTAIN : Michael has been my life 's obsession .
I 've examined every single case file written on him .
I was a student of Dr. Loomis before he passed away .
And then I lobbied the University of Illinois
to be assigned to Michael myself .
Any progress ?
Well , he 's been seen by over 50 clinical psychiatrists ,
and with each , many different opinions .
Dr. Loomis was the only one to see him in the wild .
And he concluded he was nothing more than pure evil .
Our patients get fresh air , sunshine ,
a view , proper exercise , healthy diet .
It pains me to see him transferred
to that less-than-desirable facility .
And there he is .
He can speak .
He just chooses not to .
I 'd love to stand closer to him , if I may .
Get a sense of his awareness , or lack of awareness .
Oh , make no mistake , he 's aware .
He was watching you as you arrived .
Perhaps you 'd like to tie your left shoelace ?
Mr. Tovoli here , the gentleman with the umbrella ,
has a fixation for such things .
Underestimate no one .
Of course .
And now step up to the yellow line .
And no further .
Do not cross the line under any circumstances .
Michael .
I 've got some people who 'd like to meet you .
Hello , Michael .
My name is Aaron Korey .
I 've been following your case for years
and still know very little about you .
I 'd like to know more .
About that night .
About those involved .
Do you ever think about them , Michael ?
Feel guilt about their fate ?
I borrowed something from a friend
at the attorney general 's office , Michael .
♪ ♪
You feel it , don 't you , Michael ?
- You feel the mask . - ( PATIENT WHIMPERS )
Figaro . Figaro !
( WHIMPERS )
- ( SHUSHING ) - ( DOG BARKING )
AARON : Say something , Michael .
- ( PATIENTS GRUNTING ) - ( DOG BARKING )
Say something .
( PATIENTS GRUNTING AND MOANING )
( LAUGHING HYSTERICALLY )
( BARKING )
( MOANS )
You can feel it , can 't you ?
- It 's a part of you , Michael . - ( PATIENTS GRUNTING , WHOOPING )
- ( GROANING ) - ( WHOOPS )
It 's a part of you .
( PATIENTS YELLING , WHOOPING )
Say something .
( BUZZING OVER LOUDSPEAKER )
Say something , Michael .
- ( YELLS ) - ( BARKING CONTINUES )
- ( WHOOPING ) - ( BUZZING CONTINUES )
( GRUNTING , MOANING )
( YELLS )
( MOANING )
Say something !
♪ ♪
DANA ( WHISPERS ) : What is it we 're after ?
AARON : Okay , well ,
having witnessed the animal in its captive state
and failed to provoke any sort of response ,
we now track down its counterpart .
Could it be that one monster has created another ?
And although the iron bars and barbed wire
that separate them are both strong and sharp ,
the metaphysical lines are blurred and slight .
Both exist in isolation , fettered by their own fear
- and hatred of one another . - DANA : This one .
AARON : Here ?
Could it be that the only hope
- of rehabilitation ... - DANA : Spooky .
AARON : ... is through confrontation ?
DANA : " Access has been denied .
- Private property . No trespassing . " - ( SCOFFS )
You might need this .
Dana , journalists don 't pay for their interviews .
Smile .
We 're on camera .
( BUZZES )
( BEEPING )
- ( CLICK ) - LAURIE : Yes .
AARON : Hello . Um , we 're looking for Laurie Strode .
We 're , uh , um ...
we 're-we 're making a podcast , and , uh ...
We 're investigative journalists .
If you have a moment , we 've traveled a very long way .
How does $ 3,000 sound ?
( GATE CLANKING AND CREAKING )
( JINGLING QUIETLY )
( CAR PULLING UP )
( BUZZING )
( CLUNKING )
Hello .
May we come in ?
And-and sit down and talk ?
( BEEPS )
So ...
Aaron and I have made several
award-winning public radio exposés .
Our last project shed new light
on a murder case from 20 years ago .
We like to reexamine incidents with an unbiased lens .
I believe there 's a lot to learn
from the horrors you experienced .
There 's nothing to learn .
There are no new insights
or discoveries .
So , is he real ?
Who ?
The Boogeyman .
I read you quoted ...
You don 't believe in the Boogeyman ?
I believe in Michael Myers , deranged serial killer , but ...
the Boogeyman , no .
Well , you should .
Okay .
Michael Myers is a human being
who killed his sister when he was six years old .
Then he came after you .
We just want to know why .
We want a glimpse inside his mind .
That 's why your story is so important .
My story ?
AARON : Two failed marriages .
Rocky relationship with your daughter and granddaughter .
Michael Myers murdered five people .
And he 's a human being we need to understand ?
I 'm twice divorced .
And I 'm a basket case .
They 're transferring him .
Tomorrow , 7 : 00 .
He 'll-he 'll be locked away until the end of his days .
That 's the idea .
Let 's talk about when the state came
to take your daughter away .
She was 12 years old .
They said you were an unfit mother .
How long until you regained custody ?
I didn 't .
But you already knew that .
Laurie , we saw him .
We met with Michael .
I showed him the mask .
There was nothing .
No response . Nothing .
He won 't talk to anyone .
Never has , but ...
I think he might speak with you .
So , why don 't you sit down with him
and say all the things you must be longing to say .
Come with us ,
and let us help you free yourself .
Please .
LAURIE : Time 's up .
I 'll accept my payment .
Get out .
You want to shit under my sink ?
I will murder you and your whole family .
- ( CHUCKLES ) - ( SIZZLING )
I switched from marshmallow fluff to peanut butter .
See if those little bastards eat that .
- That ought to kill them . - Morning .
I rescheduled my last session , so I can make it tonight .
You really didn 't have to do that , Mom .
It 's not a big deal .
RAY : You made it into the National Honor Society .
- KAREN : Yeah . - That is a very big deal .
I just made it to the top of my shop class ,
making birdhouses and , uh , a checkerboard made of teak .
- ( CHUCKLES ) - We 're excited to meet Cameron .
That whole family , though , they had a reputation .
- KAREN : Ray , come on . - RAY : But it 's true .
- It 's a relevant factor . - Ray .
- Ray . - Do you remember the one time Lonnie
punched that cop in the face ?
- Ray . - That was a ...
- ( TRAP SNAPS ) - Oh ! Mother ...
Oh , man !
I got peanut butter on my penis .
- ( RAY GROANS ) - Ew , Dad .
Instant karma .
Cameron is a good guy . He 's nothing like that .
You 're gonna see when you meet him tonight .
They 're all nice guys until they get you pregnant ,
and then you gotta drive in their pickup trucks ,
and you clean their guns , and you got children ,
and you clean guns , and you like to get high with them ,
and then y 'all get fat .
Hey , Dad ?
- What ? - Can you stop ?
I gotta clean this peanut butter off my hand .
Did you invite Grandmother like you said you would ?
About tonight . You said that you 'd ...
- Oh . - ... invite her .
Right . I did .
- You did ? - Yeah .
I talked to her yesterday .
She 's not gonna be able to come , honey . I 'm sorry .
Really ?
Yeah .
Baby , she 's agoraphobic .
She needs cognitive behavioral therapy ,
- so don 't take it personally . - ( DOORBELL RINGS )
That 's Vicky . I gotta go .
Hey , I love you .
Have a good day .
- ALLYSON : Bye , Dad . Love you . - RAY : Okay .
ALLYSON : So , my mom 's a liar .
VICKY : What happened ?
( SIGHS ) She said that she invited
my grandmother tonight , but she didn 't .
I mean , she never even contacted her .
- How do you know ? - Because I called her myself .
- That 's bullshit . - Yeah .
Dude , what 's your mom 's deal ? Why would she say that ?
I don 't know . She just tries to keep me away from her .
Everyone in my family , like ,
turns into a total nutcase this time of year .
If I were you guys , I wouldn 't celebrate , either .
I would just put up a Christmas tree instead .
Just skip all over the creepy Halloween shit , right ?
Does your grandma ever talk about it ?
Yeah , it 's pretty much all she talks about .
It defines her life .
She 's been traumatized ever since .
Wasn 't it her brother who , like ,
cold-blooded murdilated all those teenagers ?
No .
That 's just a bit that some people made up
to make them feel better , I think .
I mean , that is scary to have a bunch of your friends
get butchered by some random crazy person .
Is it , though ? Because , all things considered ,
there 's a lot worse stuff that 's happening today .
And , like , I mean , what , a couple people getting killed
by one guy with a knife is not that big of a deal .
Dude , her grandmother was almost fucking murdered .
And she escaped , and they caught him ,
and now he 's incarcerated .
I-I 'm just saying , like , by today 's standards ...
Just shut the fuck up , Dave .
Shut up .
Oh , I 'm sorry . Yeah , shut up , Dave .
Hey , is it cool with you guys
if I explode one of these pumpkin heads ?
( BOTH LAUGHING )
- Yeah . Yeah . - Go for it .
VICKY : Oh , he 's serious ?
- He 's serious . - Oh , God , he 's really blowing it up .
I know . He 's such a fucking moron .
- Oh , God . Oh , God . - Oh , Jesus .
- ( LAUGHING ) - Go , go , go , go , go .
- DAVE : Happy Halloween ! - ( WHISTLES , EXPLODES )
- Ah ! - ( GRUNTS )
( CHUCKLING ) : Cameron .
I got you . That was a good one .
Yes , that was very good .
Hey , do you have everything
for your costume tomorrow night ?
- Bonnie and Clyde must roll as one , after all . - Um ...
no , I mean , I-I 'm more focused on tonight .
Tonight ?
I-I thought you were joking when you said
your parents were old-fashioned .
- Be nice , okay ? - Okay .
It 'll be fun .
- I 'm excited for tonight . - I need to calm down .
- I 'm excited for tonight , okay ? - Okay .
- ( GRUNTS ) Ooh ... - ( ALLYSON CHUCKLES )
Ugh . You guys are just barf , you know .
You 're just ... you 're two yucky dumpsters ,
- and I want to go diving . Come here . Mwah ! - No .
- Dude , dude . - Right here , right here , right ?
- Oh . Mwah , mwah . - CAMERON : Dude , you-you got
your little chapped-lip crusties
all over me , man , so thanks .
I know . And you 're welcome .
- It 's gross . - It 's a little part of me for you .
For the rest of your day .
( CHUCKLING ) : All right ? So , do you have
everything ready for your costume tomorrow ?
- Um ... about that ... - What ?
Are we seriously not ?
You said we were gonna do this whole Halloween dance together .
Now-now you just ... you ditch me .
I mean , you just ... you-you can 't walk
- all over town breaking hearts . - Okay , okay , okay .
- Hey , listen , listen . - All right ?
- Love . Truly . - Okay , lovebirds , later .
- ( SCHOOL BELL RINGING ) - ( STUDENTS MURMURING )
TEACHER : Now let 's open our books to ...
Frankl 's interpretation .
He said , " Fate took a different course .
" I understand how someone who has nothing left in this world
may still know bliss . "
His message is totally hopeful .
Even in the most disparaging of conditions ,
life can find its meaning ,
and conversely , so can one 's suffering .
ALLYSON : I ...
can 't accept this .
Use it for whatever your heart desires .
I 'll save it for college , then .
Fuck college .
Go somewhere . Go to Mexico .
Could you imagine ?
Yeah , I can .
Look , don 't worry about your mom .
She will freak .
But she 'll get over it .
Why can 't you ?
The Boogeyman ?
All this hiding , all this preparation ,
it was for nothing .
I mean , it took priority over your family .
It cost you your family .
If the way I raised your mother means that she hates me
but that she 's prepared
for the horrors of this world , then ...
I can live with that .
( SHUDDERING BREATH )
Say good-bye to Michael , and get over it .
Good-bye .
( GUNSHOTS )
( CLICK )
MAN ( OVER SPEAKER ) : Dr. Samuel Loomis ,
January 22 , 1979 .
Do you wish to give a statement regarding
your former patient , Michael Myers ?
LOOMIS : My suggestion is termination .
Death is the only solution for Michael .
GUARD : A2201 . Myers , Michael .
- Toes in line . Keep a line . - LOOMIS : There 's nothing
- to be gained from keeping evil alive . - Hands up !
Hands up ! Stand up !
A22 ...
- ( STUN GUN CLICKING ) - ( SCREAMING )
LOOMIS : A shot of sodium thiopental
would render him unconscious .
- GUARD : A22 ... - I 'll be with him to make sure
- his life is extinguished . - ( GUARD CONTINUES INDISTINCTLY )
My ear on his chest to hear for myself
that his vitals no longer function
and immediately incinerate the body .
It needs to die .
( DISTORTED ) : It needs to die !
♪ ♪
( SHACKLES JINGLING )
( QUIET CHATTER )
LOOMIS : It needs to die !
GUARD : Keep moving . Let 's go .
Don 't worry , Michael .
I 'll be by your side .
( SHUDDERING BREATHS )
SARTAIN : Michael Myers is still my patient
until he 's in somebody else 's care ,
so I 'm seeing my duty through till the end .
OFFICER : All right , move out .
( BUZZING )
( BUZZING GROWS LOUDER )
( SCREAMS )
KAREN : ... send my DNA away to a stranger .
Why not ? You can find out some pretty interesting things .
- Don 't ... - I found out that I 'm part Cherokee .
I guess my dad 's , like , seven percent Cherokee .
I know Lonnie . I went to high school with him .
- He used to sell me peyote . - ALLYSON : Dad .
- KAREN : Everyone knows Lonnie . - RAY : Yeah . - Dad .
- I 'm sorry . - All right . Um ...
this is a massive overshare
- for our new friend . - No , he did .
I learned a lot about myself with his dad .
- Tripped balls out in the woods , me and his dad . - Dad .
- KAREN : Boy , Ray ... - Tripping balls . - Dad !
( LAUGHTER )
KAREN : No , really , keep talking .
So , you guys have big plans for tomorrow
- at the high school ? - RAY : What are you doing ?
- Is it a dance or something ? - Yeah , it 's a Halloween ...
- Costumes ? - Halloween dance . Yep .
- KAREN : Mmm ! - Costume party .
What are you going as ?
Uh , well , I don 't know if I 'm allowed to say .
- Please say . - KAREN : Oh , come on .
- RAY : Come on . - I can ... ? Okay .
Uh , so we 're going as Bonnie and Clyde .
- Oh , that 's a great idea . - RAY ( CHUCKLES ) : Yeah .
- Except ... - Oh !
- Oh . No . - RAY : Ooh .
Okay , so just Bonnie and Clyde .
That 's it . Bonnie and Clyde .
RAY : Bonnie and Clyde with a twist .
- Classic . - CAMERON : Yeah !
- Yeah ! - I love that . - Nice .
- That 's so fun . - You 'll see .
You know how it ended , right ?
- Their story ended a little ... - CAMERON : Yes . Hopefully ...
RAY : Yes , with the bullets and the bleeding .
- Yeah . - RAY : You have a jalopy
filled with bullet holes from the G-men ?
CAMERON : I wish we had one of those .
- RAY : It was in Laughlin , like a Model A. - KAREN : I know .
Did you talk to Grandmother ?
( SIGHS ) Yeah .
She said she was gonna come .
She came to my office . We had a nice talk .
Did you ? Really ?
- That 's a first . - It was nice .
- Oh . - Do you know where she is , then ?
- I 'm sorry . I 'm so sorry . I ... - That part ... Oh .
- KAREN : Great timing , Mom . Hi . - LAURIE : Uh , I ...
- You made it . - It ran late . I 'm sorry .
- Hi . I 'm so happy you came . - Hi , Mom . - Hi , Laurie .
- Hi . Hi . I 'm , uh ... - CAMERON : Hi .
I 'm the grandmother .
Nice to meet you . I 'm Cameron Elam .
RAY : And we 're here celebrating our daughter
- because of her ... - Yes , I know .
How did it go ?
Yes . It looks good on you .
You know , I was in the Honor Society , too .
That 's good . Why don 't you sit down , Mom ?
- No , I 'm good . - Yeah , have a seat .
Or we could go for a walk , if you 'd like .
- Really ? Did it go great ? Yeah ? - Yeah .
It went really ... it went , um ...
- KAREN : Hey , Mom ? - RAY : That 's mine .
- I thought you quit drinking . - Mmm .
Mom , what are you doing ? What is this ?
You know , this is exactly why we don 't reach out .
Mom .
LAURIE : I 'm sorry . I will sit down .
Okay .
Why don 't we press the reset button ?
Why don 't we just start over , okay ?
Mm-hmm .
KAREN : All right , Mom ...
- ( CRYING ) : Sorry . - KAREN : Mom .
RAY : Please stop this .
( LAURIE SOBBING )
LAURIE : Sorry .
I saw him .
The Shape .
- Mom ... - I wanted to kill him .
RAY : Okay , that 's enough , Laurie .
- Laurie , that 's enough . - I didn 't know what to do .
- That 's enough , Laurie . - KAREN : Okay .
I think maybe this is a little bit too much for you , huh ?
Why don 't we go for a walk , all right ?
You said you were gonna try
- to put the past behind you . - RAY : Laurie .
KAREN : Okay ? Are you gonna try to do that ?
That 's what you said you wanted to do .
LAURIE : I can 't .
Mom , look at me .
Look at me .
- I ... - CAMERON : Should we , uh
really hate to say I told you so , but ...
♪ ♪
I 'm glad you got to see that .
I never told you how I spent my childhood .
( PANTING )
( WHISPERS ) : Gotcha .
I learned how to shoot a gun when I was eight .
I learned how to fight .
I had nightmares about the basement .
( TOOL SCREECHING )
Social Services came when I was 12 years old and took me away .
( CREAKING )
I 've spent my entire life trying to get over the paranoia
and neuroses that she has projected on me .
CAMERON : Yeah , he kind of reminds me
of , uh , Gary Hogeboom .
RAY : Yeah , that quarterback thing is all messed up .
ALLYSON : Good times , right ?
What is she gonna do with herself ?
RAY : I know . It 's not your job to save her .
She 'll be all right .
- ( STATIC CRACKLING AND BUZZING ) - MAN : I can 't get reception
on this thing ever since the antenna
was bent at the car wash .
Why do we have to come out again ?
We do this all the time .
What ? You don 't ... you don 't enjoy it ?
I-I like being out in the woods and ...
No , I enjoy it , but I 'm missing dance class for this .
And sometimes I would rather do that than hunting .
I mean , is-is-is dance class that important to you ?
- Yeah , it is . - You need some more time
- in the woods to go hunting and fishing . - No .
On weekends , I 'll do it with you , Dad .
Like , I really love spending time with you ,
but right now dancing is my thing , you know , and ...
it really hits me in the heart . I mean , I ...
- Dad , look out ! - Oh !
( TIRES SQUEALING )
( BOY PANTING )
What the hell happened to you , Hoss ?
Oh , shit .
Dad , look .
Lumpy , you stay here .
I 'm gonna make sure no one 's hurt .
- You call the police . - Okay .
Dad , be careful , please .
Hey , you fellas okay ?
( OVER RADIO ) : ♪ I wish I had you all alone ♪
You all right ?
♪ Just the two of us ♪
- ( LOUD BANG ) - ( GASPS )
( PANTING )
♪ I would hold you close ... ♪
( LINE RINGING )
OPERATOR : 911 . What is the emergency ?
Yes . Um , th-there 's been an accident .
Uh , there 's a bus .
People running around in the road .
My dad went to look . I-I don 't know .
Okay . Hold on .
I 'll go check .
♪ I would hold you close ♪
♪ Close to me ♪
♪ So close to me ... ♪
Dad ?
( PANTING QUIETLY )
( DISTANT LAUGHTER )
( FAINTLY ) : ♪ Close to me ... ♪
( GASPS )
( GASPING )
- ( GROWLS , GRUNTS ) - ( BOY GRUNTS , PANTS )
MAN ( WEAKLY ) : Run .
BOY : Wait here .
I-I 'll go get my dad .
N-No .
Run !
( GASPING )
Dad !
Daddy !
- ( PAINED GRUNT ) - ( BANGING )
( PANTING )
Don 't shoot . Aah !
- Oh , fuck ! - Fuck ! ( GROANS )
( GRUNTS )
( PANTING )
( GRUNTING , PANTING )
( ENGINE STARTS )
( MUFFLED GRUNTING AND GAGGING )
( CRUNCH )
( MUSIC PLAYING SOFTLY OVER SPEAKERS )
" Don 't need a credit card to ride this train . "
Yo , Hawk , listen , the ball come down loose , that 's where
- you 're gonna mess up at . - Yo , Hawkins , would you like
a strawberry slushie or a blue raspberry slushie ?
Can you just bring me a coffee , will you ?
I 'll get you back later .
Pull a slingshot , it 'll go straight down the middle .
But you ain 't never gonna beat my score ,
so it makes no difference what you do .
- Say that again . - You 're never gonna
beat my score , so it doesn 't make no difference what you do .
MAN ( OVER RADIO ) : Dispatch to unit 601 .
We have a 10-50 on Marla Road .
Copy that , dispatch . I 'm on my way .
( SIREN WAILING )
( SIREN STOPS )
DISPATCHER ( OVER RADIO ) : Attention , all units .
We got an officer that 's 10-23
and a possible 10-50 on Route 20 . Will advise .
Sheriff 's Department .
( OVER RADIO ) : Possible 10-98 . Over .
If you need assistance , let yourself be known .
Signal 13 .
Officer down .
I repeat : officer down .
I need assistance . Send backup right away .
( RADIO BEEPS )
( OVER RADIO ) : Uh , roger that .
Ten-one , officer down .
Sending EMT and all available units .
( SIGHS ) : Ooh .
Show your hands !
( QUIET , WEAK BREATHING )
I 've been shot .
All right , stay with me . Help 's on the way .
What happened in here ?
Did he escape ?
Who ?
Did who escape ?
WOMAN : Well , I got a cousin works at a graveyard
- not too far from here . - Hmm .
They got war generals ,
philanthropists , a beatnik poet .
They got Muddy Waters .
Oh , and they got Bernie Mac .
People come from all over to pay respects .
But this is Haddonfield ,
and this is our only claim to fame .
Maybe you can explain to me
what 's so special about Judith Myers .
As she sat combing her hair , unaware ,
her six-year-old brother crept in quietly
with a kitchen knife .
AARON : He then proceeded to slice the base of her skull ,
scraping her spinal cord .
When she turned ,
raising her hands in self-defense ,
he continued stabbing
into the nerves and arteries of her palms .
Three more stabs into her sternum ,
penetrating her heart .
( CROWS CAWING )
( QUIET CHATTER )
SHERIFF BARKER : Hawkins .
Still checking I.D. 's of the patients we recovered
to figure out who 's who .
Almost all accounted for .
Two of them were checking their e-mails at a local library .
Just found three of ' em holding hands ,
chasing butterflies at a flea market off the 220 .
HAWKINS : Butterflies ?
Still no idea what really went down .
Any word from Mr. Rip van Winkle over here ?
HAWKINS : Nurses say he 's been in and out ,
lost a lot of blood .
Somehow managed to fall on a bullet .
I 'm trying to get the whole story
because here 's my concern :
Take a look at this list .
Most of ' em minor offenders , mental patients .
One stuck out : A2201 .
It 's Michael Myers .
Babysitter Murders , 1978 .
40 years to this day .
Michael Myers loose with a bunch of nutbags
in Haddonfield on Halloween night ?
We 're gonna have a fucking circus on our hands .
But hey .
What are we gonna do ?
Cancel Halloween ?
( LAUGHING )
WOMAN ( OVER P.A. ) : Dr. Ray , please pick up line two .
( ELECTRIC TOOL WHIRRS IN DISTANCE )
( BRAKES SQUEAK )
I need to go do a number two almost immediately .
- MAN : Can I drive ? - Come on , get in the car . Move it .
( ELECTRIC TOOLS RATTLE AND WHIRR IN DISTANCE )
Want anything from the shop ?
No . No , thank you .
( TOOL CLANGS ON GROUND IN DISTANCE )
Hmm .
- Where 's the loo ? - Excuse me ?
Bathroom .
It 's out that way , around the back .
( DOOR OPENS , ELECTRONIC BELL CHIMES )
( HINGES SQUEAK )
( GROANS )
( DOOR HITS WALL )
( DOOR CREAKS )
( ONE FOOTSTEP )
( HINGES SQUEAK )
( FOOTSTEPS )
( GASPS SOFTLY )
( ONE FOOTSTEP )
- ( RATTLING DOOR ) - Excuse me . Sorry .
Someone 's in here .
Hello ?
( DOOR OPENS )
( MECHANICAL WHIRRING , AIR HISSING )
( WHISPERS ) : What the ... ?
( GASPS , WHIMPERS )
( SHUDDERING GASPS )
( SOBS )
Help me ! ( GASPS )
( CRYING ) : Aah ! Help me !
Aaron ! Aaron !
( BANGS HEAD )
( CRIES OUT )
( SCREAMS )
Aah ! Get off me !
( LOCKS DOOR )
- ( POUNDING , RATTLING ) - Aaron ! Stop !
Help me !
Michael .
Aaron ! Aaron !
( GRUNTING )
- ( HEAD THUMPS ) - ( DANA GASPS )
( AARON 'S HEAD THUMPING )
Dana !
- No ! - No , please .
( GRUNTS )
( DANA SOBBING )
( SCREAMS )
( GRUNTS )
D-Dana !
( DANA SCREAMS )
( SOBBING ) : Aaron .
( SOBBING LOUDLY )
( CHOKING )
( GASPING ) : No ! No ...
♪ ♪
( SLOW , HEAVY BREATHING )
NEWSMAN : Police have not determined
a cause of this accident .
Uh , this scene 's still very active , of course .
You can see the police tape set up behind me .
That prison bus firmly down in that ditch .
You can see the tow truck , of course ,
that is trying to get that prison bus out .
A source tells us that bus
was transporting personnel from a local state hospital .
FEMALE DISPATCHER ( OVER RADIO ) : 13 A-9 .
( MALE DISPATCHER SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY )
- ( OVER RADIO ) : Roger . - ( CLICK )
( WHIRRING , SCRAPING )
( INDISTINCT CHATTER CONTINUES OVER RADIO )
( WHIRRING STOPS WITH AN ECHOING THUMP )
( PANTING SOFTLY )
( HAPPY SHOUTS , SQUEALS )
( FAINT CREAKING )
( FAINT CREAKING CONTINUES )
Ray ?
Allyson ?
Allyson ? Is anyone home ?
- Karen ? - Shh .
What ?
- Gotcha ! - ( GASPS ) - Jesus .
You 're dead .
You scared me !
What are you doing in our house ?
You mean , how did I get into your house ?
You have no security system , Karen .
Your side window was wide open .
Sometimes I can 't tell the difference
between your stupidity and your ignorance .
RAY : Hey , Laurie , this is my home ,
and I can take care of my own family , all right ?
I know jujitsu . I have studied ...
- The bus crashed . - KAREN : Ray .
- What ? - Look , I have a plan .
Where 's Allyson ? We need to get out of here now .
What bus crashed ?
- Put down that gun . Put down ... - Hey , hey . Back off !
Put down that gun . You 're in my ... Put down the gun !
KAREN : Mom , you need help ,
and you are not welcome in this house until you get it .
I have tried to protect you and prepare you .
Now we have to hunt him down .
Yeah , and I am trying to prepare dinner for my family .
The world is not a dark and evil place .
It is full of love and understanding ,
and I 'm not letting your psychotic rants confuse me
or convince me otherwise .
- Keep the gun . - No ! You need to go .
Get out !
( INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER )
♪ ♪
( WHISPERS ) : Son of a bitch .
( SIGHS )
BARKER : Hawkins .
Frank !
Yeah ?
Look at this .
- It 's a hospital gown . - State-issued .
Get on the phone to Smith 's Grove .
Confirm the match .
You know I was there that night . You know .
I was there .
We have one order of business .
That 's to hunt this thing down .
There 's a reason we 're supposed to be afraid of this night .
- Trick or treat ! - Trick or treat !
( LIVELY CHATTER )
- ( POPPING , CRACKLING ) - ( SHRIEKS )
BOY : Which one should we go to ?
BOY 2 : They 're all spooky .
I 'm gonna pick that one
over , um , across the street .
- ( GASPS ) - Oh , oh , oh , oh .
- What the ... ? Sorry . - Hey . Sorry about that .
♪ ♪
KIDS ( CHANTING ) : Black cats and goblins
and broomsticks and ghosts ,
Covens of witches with all of their hosts ,
You may think they scare me ,
You 're probably right ,
Black cats and goblins on Halloween night .
♪ ♪
( MAN SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY ON TV )
( WOMAN ON TV CRYING , GASPING )
WOMAN : Please !
- Please let us out of here ! - Where did they come from ?
( INDISTINCT , PANICKED CHATTER )
( MOVIE CONTINUES INDISTINCTLY )
( WOMAN GASPS )
( HAMMER STRIKING )
- ( WOMAN GRUNTING ) - ( HAMMER CONTINUES STRIKING )
( BABY CRYING IN DISTANCE )
MAN ( ON TV ) : You are from the other side .
You are the sign .
( BABY CONTINUES CRYING )
( BABY CALMS )
♪ ♪
( DOOR CREAKS )
( LIVELY CHATTER )
- KIDS : Trick or treat ! - MAN : Hey , guys . Stay together .
MAN : Very scary .
- WOMAN : Mila . Mila , no ! - KIDS : Trick or treat ...
- Wait your turn . - ... smell my feet ,
- give me something good to eat . - MAN : Wait , hang on , hang on .
- I don 't have my stethoscope . - Come on !
- I need it . I 'm gonna get it . - We 're going to be late .
- I 'll be right back . - Geez !
Look . You 're not gonna believe this .
They were in my pocket the whole time .
Did Rebecca give you directions ?
Yeah . She did call me .
( CAR DOORS CLOSE )
( ENGINE STARTS )
( PHONE RINGS )
WOMAN : Hey , Sally . How are you ?
Really ?
That 's awful .
Well , I 'll keep my doors locked .
( MICHAEL 'S MUFFLED BREATHING )
Thanks for telling me .
Billy 's still out at a party .
Let me know if you hear anything else .
♪ ♪
Good night , Sally .
( GASPS , SCREAMS )
( GASPS )
KIDS : Trick or treat !
OSCAR : Bonnie and Clyde , you are lady-killers .
You guys are seriously beautiful .
You 're seriously beautif ... Give me a smile .
Give me a big smile . Just hold her tight .
There we go . Do that . Do that with your ass . ( LAUGHS )
( ELECTRONIC DANCE MUSIC PLAYING )
♪ I had this feeling I was staring ♪
♪ Straight into the sun ♪
♪ But I can 't walk away ♪
♪ So I just want to crash and burn ... ♪
- ( PHONE RINGING ) - OSCAR : Okay , so , no , not ...
It 's Vicky . One second . One sec .
♪ I 'm trying to break free ... ♪
Okay , you don 't ... you don 't have to take it .
♪ But when you comfort me ... ♪
Hi . Oh , my gosh , I wish that you were here .
It is so much fun .
God , I wish I was there . I 'm so fuckin ' bummed .
It 's just , like , so much easier
to actually , like , talk to people when you have no idea
- who they are . - Yeah , dude , I told you you 'd have fun .
How 's Cameron ? Is he looking super fine
in my grandma 's skirt ?
He is ...
so sexy , it 's a little too much to take .
- ( BEEP ) - But ...
- VICKY : Where 'd you go ? - No , he 's so sweet .
- I 'm having the best time . - You know , you guys
should just come over here when it 's done .
Dave 's already on his way , and he 's gonna bring the , uh ,
you know , the " Alakazam , " if you know what I mean .
And Julian 's parents aren 't gonna be back
until , like , super late .
Okay , well , it is a school night ,
so we 're not gonna ... " kazam " too much .
Oh , come on . It 's a " school night . "
Don 't be a needy bitch . Get over here .
Okay . I 'll see you soon . We 'll come over
- as soon as it 's over . - Okay , bye . Love you .
I heard you telling your friends to come over here
- and you 're gonna smoke some weed . - No . No .
- That " Alakazam " ? - Julian , I 'm talking about ,
like , uh , you know , like , a ma-magic trick ,
- like , " abracadabra . " - I know you 're talking
about smoking weed . Don 't lie to me .
That 's against the rules . I 'm telling my mom .
Well , I 'm gonna tell your mom about your browser history .
- You better not . - You can get me in trouble ,
- I can get you in trouble . - I 'm ...
You used to be my favorite , but now you 're ,
like , my tenth favorite boy that I nanny .
And I babysit some fucking loser kids .
If I had some other kind of babysitter ,
she 'd be reading me a story .
I wouldn 't be up clipping my nasty-ass toenails .
- Uh-huh . Go to bed . - You used to be cool .
We used to be friends . But now ...
( LAUGHS ) : Okay . Come on , go to bed .
- Wait . - It 's way past your bedtime .
- You want to be a good kid ? - Mm-hmm .
- Mm-hmm . Go to bed , go to bed . - How much do you get paid ?
Come on , let 's go , let 's go .
VICKY : I 'll get ya . Come on .
( SCREAMING OVER TV )
( KISS ) Good night , little dude .
Hey , Vicky .
Can you leave the door open ? Just a crack ?
Yeah .
Good night .
By the way , you 're actually my favorite kid I babysit for .
I like you , too .
Good night .
( CRICKETS CHIRPING SOFTLY )
♪ I don 't play , I don 't play ♪
♪ Get your boy in the other lane ♪
♪ Get your boy in the other lane , he know better ♪
♪ He know better than try to step to me ♪
♪ He know better ♪
♪ He know better than to think ♪
♪ I 'd come for free , he know better ♪
♪ He know better than to think I 'd go for that ♪
♪ He know better , he know better ♪
♪ All up in my face , all up in my grill , boy ♪
♪ 2008 , still trying to be hot , boy ♪
♪ Y 'all think this is lame ♪
♪ Y 'all think this is lame , boy ♪
♪ Nah , homie , I 'm straight ♪
♪ Nah , homie , I 'm good , boy ♪
♪ Got my girls and I got my hair ♪
♪ Like I 'm goin ' to Coachella ... ♪
That is not what ...
CAMERON : Fuck . Okay , that really ...
that fucked me up . Okay .
♪ Unless it 's André 3K , Big Sean or Fetty Wap ... ♪
Allyson !
Allyson , come here !
( MUSIC , CHATTER CONTINUE IN DISTANCE )
- Wait . Hey , Allyson . - No . What was that ?
- Okay , what ? What ? Hey , wh ... - What was that ?
- What ? - What 's this ?
What ? Dude , have some discretion , all right ?
I don 't know what you thought you saw , but , like ,
I ... Kim ... literally was talking to me .
- Really ? - She came up to me and , like ,
whispered in my ear , okay ?
You don 't have to cry about it .
It 's not that big a deal .
- So Oscar got you fucked up ? - No , I got ...
I mean , I got me fucked up . I ...
- Okay . - ( PHONE RINGING )
- Hey , okay , can we just talk ? Okay . - Don 't .
Okay , here , you know what ? No .
Your fucking precious phone ?
- ( MUFFLED RINGING ) - ( CHUCKLES )
What the fuck ?
You gonna get that ?
Or you want me to get it ?
♪ They tryin ' to hate me , pullin ' all their fellas ♪
♪ We don 't want ' em , we ain 't got time for that ♪
♪ Unless it 's André 3K , Big Sean or Fetty Wap ... ♪
Hold ... hold up , hold up . Wait , wait , wait .
I 'm done .
♪ Get your boy in the other lane ♪
♪ Get your boy in the other lane ... ♪
OFFICER : This is Unit 14 .
- I 'm out by Old Lady Miller 's house . - Oh , shit .
I don 't see anything suspicious out here . Over .
DISPATCHER : Uh , ten-four . You want to go ahead and , uh ,
show yourself code two , officially cancel
request for assistance ?
OFFICER : Uh , affirmative . Over .
- ( MICHAEL 'S MUFFLED BREATHING ) - ( CRICKETS CHIRPING )
( TRASH CAN CLANGING )
- ( IMITATES NEIGHING ) - Oh , shit .
- Sorry . - Hi .
I didn 't want to ring the doorbell and wake up the kid .
- It 's okay . - Check it out . Fresh from my patch .
- Oh , my God . - His eyes are hearts .
- I love it . - Yeah .
- This is Tate . - Hello . Hi , Tate .
- Hello . What 's up ? - Hi . How are ya ?
Do we have the whole house to ourselves ?
- Is that how this works ? - Yes .
- Sweet . - Until Allyson and Cameron get here .
Okay , so , in the meantime , you want to make some popcorn
and watch a spooky movie ?
- Mm , no . - All right , wait , check this out .
You 're gonna like this .
I went ...
- and got this tattoo . - ( GASPS )
Because tonight is the night ,
the one we 'll remember for the rest of our lives .
You are so getting dry-fucked tonight .
- ( CHUCKLES ) Oh , yeah ? - Fuckin ' come here .
( PANTING )
( DISTANT THUMP )
What ?
- What was that ? - What was what ?
Did you hear something ?
No . What was it ?
I don 't know . I thought ...
I thought I heard , like , a noise or something .
Yeah , it 's probably just Julian taking a dump .
Would you go look ?
Do I have to ?
Yeah , would you please go look ?
Okay .
- It was weird . - All right . ( SIGHS )
All right , little buddy .
- Oh , fuck me . - I saw someone in the hallway ,
standing outside my door .
- Oh . - What 's up , buddy ?
There was a fucked-up face , watching me from the dark .
Ghosts and goblins , little buddy ?
Shut up , Dave ! I heard him breathing ,
and then I saw him . He 's in here .
Boogeyman 's in this house .
Okay . All right . Come on , I got you .
- Let 's check it out . - Send Dave first .
- No , it 's fine . It 's fine . - No , no . No , it 's not .
- It 's okay . Come on . - No , it 's not . No , it 's not .
Come on , show me where you saw Boogeyman .
- I 'll protect you . I 'm strong . I got you . - No .
- No , Vicky , you go up there first . - I 'll fight him off .
- Come on . I promise . - No .
- JULIAN : Can you call my mom ? - VICKY : Yeah .
If there 's something in the room , I 'll call her .
He was standing right there in-in the door .
VICKY : I 'll check it out .
VICKY : Excuse me , sir .
What are you doing in here ?
Please , you need to leave .
Please leave .
Vicky ?
VICKY : Get out now !
- ( GROWLS ) - ( JULIAN GASPS )
- Gotcha . - You fucking kidding me ?
You 're safe .
Nothing 's in here .
- You sure ? - Mm-hmm .
Y-You check behind the curtains ?
I checked the whole place .
( CRICKETS CHIRPING )
♪ ♪
Sick .
VICKY : See ? There 's nothing to be afraid of .
There 's no Boogeyman in here .
What if it 's a doll ?
Ooh , it could be , like , one of those weird , like , kid dolls ,
one of those weird babies , and they stare at you
- with those beady little eyes . - ( JULIAN WHIMPERS )
( ENGINE REVVING )
( LAUGHING ) : Oh , fuck , that was ... Oh !
Ah , sharia .
( GRUNTS )
Uh , c-could you close the closet door ?
Yeah .
( SCREAMS , GRUNTS )
- Oh , shit ! - ( VICKY WHIMPERING )
( GRUNTS ) Oh , God .
No !
Oh ! ( GRUNTS )
( VICKY SOBS , GRUNTS )
( VICKY SCREAMS )
( GRUNTING , SOBBING )
Help ! Dave !
Help me !
- JULIAN : Vicky ! - ( VICKY GRUNTING )
- ( SCREAMS ) - Whoa !
Julian , run !
- I 'll go get help . Dave ! Dave ! - Vicky ?
- VICKY : Get out of here ! - ( JULIAN SCREAMING )
Don 't go up there ! You 're gonna get killed , Dave .
VICKY : Somebody help me !
- Dave , help me ! - Vicky .
VICKY : No , no , no , no , no , no .
( SOBBING ) : No , no , no .
( VICKY SCREAMS )
- No ! No ! - ( KNIFE SQUISHING )
Fuck this .
( METAL SCRAPES , RINGS )
( STEADY , MUFFLED BREATHING )
DISPATCHER ( OVER RADIO ) : All units , we have reports
of a domestic disturbance at 707 Meridian Avenue .
Please respond . Over .
Copy that , Dispatch .
( TIRES SQUEALING )
MAN : Okay , guys , don 't forget to say thank you .
( INDISTINCT CHATTER )
WOMAN : Come on . That 's enough . No , come on .
MAN : No , they can have a little more , honey .
KIDS ( IN DISTANCE ) : Trick or treat , smell my feet ,
give me something good to eat .
Haddonfield Sheriff 's Department !
Responding to a domestic disturbance !
I repeat . This is Officer Hawkins .
Please respond .
♪ ♪
- ( TIRES SCREECH ) - WOMAN : Honey , watch out !
Get out of here ! Now !
Let 's go , guys . Move .
LAURIE : Get inside !
( DOOR CREAKING SOFTLY )
( BREATH TREMBLING )
HAWKINS ( GASPS ) : Fuck !
♪ ♪
( COCKS PISTOL )
Michael !
( GASPS , GROANS )
( PANTING )
( PANTING , TREMBLING )
( WHISPERS ) : Oh , shit .
( WHIMPERS )
♪ ♪
( FOOTSTEPS NEARBY )
( GASPING BREATHS )
( WHISPERS ) : Laurie . Fuck !
Jesus Christ , Frank !
- Fuck me ! - What the fuck ?
( LAURIE PANTING )
What the hell are you doing here ?
Frank , he 's here .
I know .
( SIRENS WAILING , HELICOPTER WHIRRING )
( INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER )
- ( INDISTINCT CHATTER ) - This way , please .
( DOG BARKING )
( TIRES SCREECH )
( SIREN WHOOPS )
- ( SIREN WAILS IN DISTANCE ) - BARKER : Look who 's up .
Where is he ?
You tell me .
SARTAIN : The bus lost control after Michael
overtook the first guard and the driver .
He 's no longer dormant .
He only knows how to keep moving
and to keep killing .
And he will kill again unless he 's captured .
BARKER : Come with me for a minute .
You sit still .
Well , I was sitting still anyway .
- What do you mean ? - He 's an asset .
He 's not an asset . He 's a liability .
No , no . He 's on this hunt .
Nobody knows Myers better than he does .
- Oh , thank you . - HAWKINS : You want me to take
this injured civilian to go look for
- a psychopathic serial killer ? - LAURIE : Sheriff .
Frank . Wha-What are we doing ?
We don 't need your help right now , Laurie .
You 're just standing here ! Please do something !
( WHISPERS ) : Excuse me , officers .
Laurie Strode .
BARKER : Laurie Strode , meet Dr. Sartain .
SARTAIN : I 'm Michael 's doctor .
Ranbir Sartain .
Oh , you 're the new Loomis .
I read everything about you and Michael .
Everything .
Did you know our friend Hawkins here
was the first responding deputy
when Michael was apprehended in 1978 ?
He stopped Loomis from killing Michael that night .
Do you know that I pray every night
that he would escape ?
What the hell do you do that for ?
So I can kill him .
Well , that was a dumb thing to pray for .
I 'm sure he 'll apologize . He just needs to sleep it off .
Cameron doesn 't want anyone to see him as a bad guy ,
but then he gets drunk and gets belligerent
and looks like an idiot .
( LAUGHS ) And then I look like an idiot for vouching for him .
I 'm really tired of everybody letting me down all the time .
You deserve better .
I mean ...
( SIGHS ) Allyson , you 're the coolest , you 're the prettiest ,
and you 're the nicest girl in school .
And if anyone doesn 't appreciate that ,
they 're a crazy person .
Thank you .
That 's very sweet .
Let 's get out of here .
I know a shortcut .
HAWKINS : From a clinical perspective ,
Doctor , would you say that Laurie Strode
has lost her fucking marbles ?
There are many ways for tragedy and violence
to change a victim .
They can grow accustomed to always being afraid ,
in constant fear .
They can grow weak , they can grow strong .
But there 's also the other side .
What other side is that ?
The effect on the victimizer .
You see , this is what has intrigued me
through my studies .
How does a crime like Michael 's affect him ?
Hmm ? What 's that feeling ?
Is he on a random path , or is he emotionally driven ?
Triggered by something ?
Perhaps some unheard marching order
imprinted on his very being .
I want to know what he 's feeling .
I want to know what pleasure he gets out of killing .
Where is this killer ? We gotta find him .
I 'm not gonna stand in the way of justice this time .
Remember , he 's property of the state .
- He mustn 't be harmed . - Oh , yeah ?
We 'll see about that .
( INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER )
- ♪ ♪ - ( CRICKETS CHIRPING )
( DOORBELL RINGS REPEATEDLY )
It 's not safe here .
Where 's Allyson ?
Where is she ?
Where 's Allyson ? !
Honey , it 's Mom . Can you please call me back
the second that you get this , please ?
The police said that they evacuated the dance ,
and I can 't get in touch with you .
And they 're making us go to your grandmother 's house
because it 's safe ...
Sweetheart , this is your grandmother .
There is a police officer waiting at your house
to bring you to us .
We 're all gonna be together .
Now , do as I say .
- ( STRAINED GRUNTING ) - OSCAR : Oh , shit .
It 's treacherous as hell here .
- Okay . - You good ?
- Take my hand . - Okay .
- Right here . - This is the dumbest shortcut ever .
Watch out for all the poison ivy .
- Don 't let me fall on that . - All right . I got you .
- I got you . Okay , I got you . - Okay , go .
- Oh ! - Okay .
You did it . Yay .
- ( LAUGHS ) - Good job .
Yay .
What are you doing ?
I mean , you deserve better .
- Right ? I mean ... - No ... ( GRUNTS )
What the fuck ?
I-I ... What ? You 're not with Cameron anymore .
That does not ... ( TREMBLING EXHALE )
That does not mean I want to be with you .
I thought ... I thought you were sending me signals .
- Definitely no signals . - I 'm so sorry .
Please , you cannot tell Cameron about this .
I-I didn 't feel anything , either . I swear .
- I didn 't ... Wait , I didn 't ... - You are so pathetic .
I 'm going home . You can figure your own shit out .
Sh ... Who 's there ? Wha-What ... Hey !
Motion sensor , dumb-ass !
Allyson , I 'm , like ,
really drunk right now . Seriously .
I got really horny at the party , and , like ,
all these girls were , like , dancing on me .
Their beautiful bodies got me all chubbed out , Allyson .
I ... Allyson , please !
They , like ... they were feeding me guacamole
- in all these sexy ways . - ( QUIET FOOTSTEPS NEARBY )
It 's not my ... ( SIGHS )
Happy Halloween , Mr. Elrod . I 'm-I 'm just ...
I don 't know , man . I 'm sorry .
I 'm not trying to trespass on your yard and shit , man .
I was just trying to take a shortcut
with a really pretty girl , and I just ...
( SIGHS ) I just really like her , man ,
and I-I thought that she liked me , too .
And I just ... it just ...
Have you ever really liked a girl
and you just couldn 't have her ?
I 'm s ... I 'm sorry , man .
I 'll just ... I 'll peace out of your hair , man .
Thank-thank you for ... ( STAMMERS , SIGHS )
Hey , uh ...
where 'd you go , man ? You 're acting ...
( CHUCKLING ) : Dude , you 're acting , like ,
really sketchy right now . I don 't ...
Uh ...
What 's up ?
( STEADY , MUFFLED BREATHING )
I 'm-I 'm-I 'm leaving right ... I don 't ...
I 'm ...
( OSCAR YELLS )
Ow ! Oh , my God ! Aah ! Aah !
Help me ! Help !
Please ! Somebody !
Somebody , help me , please !
Somebody , please ! Please , somebody !
Somebody , please help me ! Please !
Please , somebody , help me ! Aah !
- Aah ! Anybody ! - Oscar , come on .
Please , dear God ! Please !
Plea ... Please !
Help me ! Help me ! Help me !
Please help me !
- ♪ ♪ - ( CHOKING )
( LOW CHOKING , GURGLING )
( STEADY , MUFFLED BREATHING )
Oscar !
( ALLYSON GASPING , SHUDDERING )
( FOOTSTEPS NEARBY )
♪ ♪
( SCREAMS )
- ( KNOCKING ) - Help ! Let me in !
Let me in !
Help !
Somebody !
Help ! Help !
Please !
Help ! ( GASPING BREATHS )
KAREN : ' Cause my daughter is not calling .
OFFICER FRANCIS : It 's safer for you ...
- She 's not texting . - RAY : Come on , Karen , let 's go inside .
FRANCIS : Everyone 's looking for your daughter .
- RAY : Let them take care of it . - So whoever you had
looking for her is obviously not able to identify her .
- We 're gonna find your daughter . - It 's Halloween .
- We 're gonna bring her here . - There are kids everywhere .
- Karen , come on . - There is no way .
- Karen . Karen . - She had a costume , you know ?
- We need to go in the house . - We have everybody available ...
- In the last 40 years , okay ? - ( ALL TALKING AT ONCE )
Honey , if you let ' em do their job , they 're gonna ...
- Karen ! - ( OTHERS QUIET )
( SIREN WAILING )
WOMAN : Just breathe . And if you want , we can call ...
( TIRES SCREECH )
Stay in the car , Doctor .
- You all right ? - Take deep breaths , sweetheart .
- He 's ... he 's down the street . - Okay .
- Okay . - He 's back . He killed my friend .
Everything 's gonna be all right . It 's okay .
Take a deep breath .
We 're gonna take you back to your mom , okay ?
I 'm a doctor . Lock your doors .
Everybody , get back to your houses now and lock your doors .
We 're gonna take you to your mom .
Don 't worry about him . Don 't worry about him .
HAWKINS : Back in your houses now !
SARTAIN : You heard the officer .
- WOMAN : What is going on ? - HAWKINS : Back in your houses !
Lock your goddamn doors .
( LOCK CLICKS )
( CLICK )
( WHIRRING , SCRAPING )
What 's this ?
It 's my childhood .
Let 's go .
( LAURIE SIGHS )
♪ ♪
( CLICK )
( WHIRRING , SCRAPING )
( WHIRRING , SCRAPING STOP WITH A THUMP )
( SIGHS )
All right , pick your poison .
I like a revolver . They never jam .
This is accuracy and stopping power .
This is tactical .
He waited for this night .
He 's waited for me .
I 've waited for him .
Come on , Michael .
♪ ♪
( INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER )
Allyson , keep your eyes open .
- He is out there somewhere . - ( OVER RADIO ) : 601 .
Suspect reported on 11th , near Saint Park .
Copy that , Dispatch .
I got eyes .
Look ! It 's him !
- Here we go . - ( TIRES SQUEAL )
Brace yourselves .
( TIRES SQUEALING )
SARTAIN : Don 't hit him !
- Watch out ! - SARTAIN : Michael !
( PANTING )
( DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES )
Don 't shoot him .
- Doctor , get back in the car . - No !
You killed him . He 's dead .
- Stand back . - No .
I 'm still gonna blow this motherfucker 's brains out .
SARTAIN : Get away . Leave my patient alone .
HAWKINS : Get away from the body . Stand back .
I 'm not gonna say it again . Step away from the suspect .
- Step a ... - ( SARTAIN YELLS )
( GUN FIRES )
( ALLYSON SHUDDERING , GASPING )
( HAWKINS AND SARTAIN GRUNTING )
ALLYSON : Fuck .
Help ! Help !
Help !
( GASPING , GURGLING )
( SIGHS , GASPS )
( ALLYSON SOBBING )
So this is what it feels like .
( PANTING )
ALLYSON : Help !
( ALLYSON SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY )
( SARTAIN INHALES DEEPLY )
- ( BANGING ON WINDOW ) - ( ALLYSON SHOUTING )
( SLOW , HEAVY BREATHING )
( WHIMPERS )
( PANTING )
( SOBBING , PANTING )
( SHUDDERING , PANTING )
- Make room for my patient . - No ! ( GRUNTS )
- ( SARTAIN GRUNTING ) - ( WHIMPERING ) : No .
ALLYSON ( GRUNTS ) : No !
( EXHALES )
- ( ALLYSON SOBBING , WHIMPERING ) - ( SARTAIN SIGHS )
( ALLYSON CRYING )
These people want to kill this man
for the crimes you observed .
The most important opportunity
to understand the mind of evil , you see .
So , when he awakes , we 'll be ready .
Ready for what ?
The reunion .
Michael 's pursuit of Laurie Strode
could be what keeps him alive .
I would suspect the notion of being a predator
or the fear of becoming prey keeps both of them alive .
( SHIFTS , TIRES SQUEAL )
( BODY THUMPS UNDER TIRE )
OFFICER PHILLIPS : You want a banh mi sandwich ?
FRANCIS : A what ? What is that ?
- A banh mi sandwich . - What 's a ...
Wh-What is that ? I don 't even know what that is .
I love that about you , Francis . You 're so predictable .
You 're like a PB and J every day kind of guy .
FRANCIS : Oh , here we go .
No , a banh mi sandwich .
Banh mi is essentially just
the Vietnamese version of a French baguette .
- Mm-hmm . - And the term actually refers
to the bread and not so much the contents therein .
- Mm . - But your partner ,
- the greatest partner in the world ... - Oh .
... made an arrangement with the Vietnamese folks
- at the restaurant ... - Mm .
... and had them make you your very own
peanut butter and jelly banh mi sandwich .
That sounds disgusting .
I 'm not gonna try that . I brought my own food .
- I 'm very happy with my ... - What did you bring ?
You want to see what I brought ?
Yeah , I do want to see what you brought .
Why don 't you look at this ?
- Look at that . - Oh .
- Fresh brownie . - Okay .
Chocolaty homemade brownie . I made that myself .
That 's-that 's , like , what a five-year-old would eat
if they could make their own lunch .
SARTAIN : I worked with Michael for years ,
but I 've never seen him in an uncontrolled environment .
I 've never heard him speak , you see .
In spite of my encouragements , he remains unresponsive .
But tonight , so many possibilities exist .
He spoke to me .
- He spoke to you ? - Yeah .
Um , uh , when he murdered my friend ,
he saw me , and-and he spoke to me .
What did he say ?
- One word . - What ?
Let me go , and I will tell you what he said .
You must tell me . I must know . You must tell me .
Let me go , and I 'll tell you what he said .
Just stop the car , and I 'll tell you what he said .
( GRUNTS )
( TIRES SCREECHING )
What is that ?
PHILLIPS : That 's weird , right ?
Is that Hawkins ?
I don 't know .
What was the word ?
Was it the sister 's name ?
Judith ?
( SLOW , HEAVY BREATHING )
( WHIMPERING )
- What was the word ? - Fuck .
Michael .
( SCREAMING , GROANING )
( SCREAMING )
606 to 601 .
Hawkins .
Answer the fucking radio , burnout .
- ( HORN HONKING ) - ( OVER RADIO ) : Hawkins ?
( HONKING STOPS )
PHILLIPS ( OVER RADIO ) : 606 , 601 .
Hawkins , please respond .
Hawkins .
- Let 's go check it out . - All right .
( SLOW , HEAVY BREATHING )
Say something .
( SIREN WHOOPING )
Can you see him ?
( ECHOING OVER LOUDSPEAKER ) : Hawkins , please respond .
Hawkins , please respond .
Let 's go and check it out .
All right .
Dispatch , be advised , we got a man down .
He 's ten-seven .
No sign of 601 .
( FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING )
Karen , the lights .
KAREN : What are you doing ?
I thought you said we were safer here .
You never wanted to listen when I spoke of that night .
And this is why .
I 've been preparing for this for a long time .
You want him to come here .
I 'm so sorry , Karen . I 'm so sorry , baby .
♪ ♪
( PANTING )
( SIREN WHOOPING )
( DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES )
Any word ?
Hey , any word on Allyson ?
Hey .
Guys .
( RAY GASPS )
( RAY GASPING )
Wha ... ? ( GRUNTS )
( RAY PANTING )
( RAY GRUNTS )
( GRUNTING )
( DISTANT GUNSHOT )
( YELLS , GRUNTS )
( MUFFLED GRUNTING )
- ( RAY YELPS ) - ( NECK SNAPS )
Ray !
Karen !
Where 's Ray ?
Michael 's here . Get downstairs .
Go , baby , go !
( WHIRRING , RATTLING )
( PANTING )
( SWITCH CLICKS )
( WHIRRING , RATTLING )
- ( CLUNK ) - ( WHIRRING , RATTLING STOP )
( WHIMPERS )
( GASPING , GRUNTING )
( YELPING IN PAIN )
( GROANING )
( COUGHS , GASPS )
Mom !
( LAURIE GRUNTING )
( GASPING )
Mom !
( MUFFLED GRUNTING )
- ( GUN BLASTS ) - ( LAURIE GRUNTS )
( PANTING RAPIDLY )
( WHIRRING , RATTLING )
( BOTH PANTING )
( LIGHTS CLUNKING )
( FOOTSTEPS )
( OBJECTS CLATTERING )
( CLUNKING )
I was wrong to raise you the way I did ,
but at least I can protect you .
- Nothing will happen to you . - ( KAREN GASPING )
I know you thought this was my cage .
( HEAVY FOOTSTEPS , FLOORBOARDS CREAKING )
KAREN ( GASPS ) : I 'm scared .
( SLOW , HEAVY BREATHING )
( KAREN GASPING )
♪ ♪
( HEAVY FOOTSTEPS )
( CLUNKING )
( GUN CLICKS , SHELL CASING DROPS TO FLOOR )
( SHUDDERING BREATHS )
I have to finish this .
Mom .
( WHIMPERING ) : I love you .
I love you , baby .
( SWITCH CLICKS )
( WHIRRING , RATTLING )
- ( CLUNK ) - ( WHIRRING , RATTLING STOP )
( WHIRRING , RATTLING RESUME )
( FOOTSTEPS ABOVE )
( FOOTSTEPS CONTINUE ABOVE )
( QUIET GASPING )
Come out , Michael .
( FOOTSTEPS IN OTHER ROOM )
( CLOCK TICKING )
( RATTLING )
( LOUD CLUNK )
( GASPS )
( PANTING )
( FLOORBOARDS CREAKING )
♪ ♪
( RATTLES , CLUNKS )
( PANTING )
( GASPS , WHIMPERS )
( SHUDDERING )
( EERIE , DISTORTED GIGGLING )
( DISTORTED SHRIEK )
( WHIMPERS )
( SCREAMS )
( SCREAM FADES IN DISTANCE )
( FOOTSTEPS )
( PANTING QUIETLY )
( RATTLES , CLUNKS )
( DOOR CREAKS , BANGS OPEN )
( PANTING )
( QUIET CLINKING )
( EXHALES SHARPLY )
( LAURIE GASPS )
( PANTING )
( GRUNTS , PANTS )
( QUIET , SHUDDERING BREATHS )
( WHIMPERS )
( GASPING , GRUNTING )
( SCREAMS , GRUNTS )
( GRUNTING )
( STRAINED GRUNTING )
( GROANS )
( GRUNTING )
( WHIMPERS , SCREAMS )
( SLOW , HEAVY BREATHING )
♪ ♪
Mom .
( GASPS )
Grandmother ?
( GASPING )
ALLYSON : Grandmother ?
( PANTING )
Baby .
( GASPS ) Mom .
He 's coming . Come on .
- Shh . Come on . Come on . - Where 's Grandmother ?
( FLOORBOARDS CREAKING )
- ( HEAVY FOOTSTEPS ) - ( SLOW , HEAVY BREATHING )
I couldn 't ... I couldn 't find you guys .
- Where is everybody ? - It 's okay . It 's okay .
( CLUNK )
- ( FOOTSTEPS ABOVE ) - ( ALLYSON PANTING )
( KAREN SHUSHING )
- It 's gonna be okay . - I 'm locked in a cage .
It 's gonna be okay . It 's gonna be okay .
( DEEP CREAKING )
( WHISPERS ) : Everything 's going to be okay .
- ( SHUDDERING BREATHS ) - ( SHUSHES QUIETLY )
( SLOW , HEAVY BREATHING )
( FOOTSTEPS , CREAKING ABOVE )
( SHUDDERING ) : Mom , I 'm so sorry .
I tried to stop him from coming here .
( KAREN SHUSHES QUIETLY )
( BANGING , CREAKING )
- Okay . Okay . - ( FOOTSTEPS ABOVE )
- ( GRUNTS ) - ( BANGING )
- ( ALLYSON SHUDDERING ) - ( KAREN SHUSHING )
( BANGING , CREAKING )
( REPEATED BANGING )
♪ ♪
Stay back .
( BANGING CONTINUES )
Get back ! Get back , get back .
( GASPING ) : Oh , God .
( GASPS , SCREAMS )
( GASPING , WHIMPERING ) : Stay back .
Mom ?
Help us !
I can 't do it .
I 'm sorry . I can 't do it .
Gotcha .
( GRUNTS )
( THUDS )
- Happy Halloween , Michael . - ( BLADE RINGS )
( GRUNTS FIERCELY )
( GRUNTING , YELLING )
Come on , Allyson !
- Come on , Allyson ! - Allyson , go !
Allyson , come on !
Go !
Karen , come on , baby . Come on !
( PANTING , WHIMPERING )
Oh , God ! ( SCREAMS )
( SCREAMING , GRUNTING )
I got you !
( SCREAMING )
Allyson , run !
Go ! Go now !
LAURIE : Come on , kick him !
- KAREN : Allyson ! Allyson , go ! - LAURIE : Go !
( YELLS )
KAREN : Now go !
( SCREAMING )
( GRUNTS )
( PANTING )
( GASPING )
( GAS HISSING )
Okay . It 's not a cage , baby .
( ALL PANTING )
It 's a trap .
Good-bye , Michael .
( FLAME RUMBLING )
( WHOOSHING )
( EXPLOSIVE WHOOSH )
♪ ♪
KAREN : Oh , God , someone 's coming .
Someone 's coming .
( COUGHING )
- Hold her . - I got her .
I got her . Go !
Go , baby , go !
Hey !
Help us .
( PANTING )
♪ ♪
Subtitles by explosiveskull
( MUSIC FADES )
- ( RECORD SCRATCHES ) - ( INTRO TO " CLOSE TO ME " PLAYS )
♪ Close to me ♪
♪ Close to me ... ♪
♪ So close to me ♪
♪ I would hold you ♪
♪ Close to me ♪
♪ I wish I had you ♪
- ♪ All alone ♪ - ♪ All alone ♪
♪ Just the two of us ♪
♪ I would hold you ♪
♪ Close ♪
♪ Close to me ♪
♪ Close to me ... ♪
♪ So close to me ♪
♪ I would hold you so close ♪
♪ Close to me . ♪
- ( SONG FADES ) - ( SLOW , HEAVY BREATHING )